BALAMURUGAN PERIYASAMY

A data scientist who thrives in generating business insights, having served in multiple roles in the data domain. My inputs have led to raising capital, feasibility of new product launches and cutting costs. MBA(Finance,IT) from IIT Delhi. BE (Computer science) from Amrita University, Coimbatore.



INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

Current 2017-01

Vice President

Goldman Sachs

PBengaluru, India

- · Co-Leading Analytics Securitised Derivatives team on a portfolio of \$100 billion AUM; Part of Sales Strategists in Global Markets Division
- · Implemented forecasting model to predict every quarter net sales to Structured Derivatives business. Output is used by Corporate Treasury for firmwide budgeting.
- · Point of contact for business data and insights provided to external stakeholders like Regulators and data vendors through notebooks.
- · Setup data warehouse in Sybase and Postgres DB. Created ETL process from scratch for Structured and Funds business as part of digitization strategy. Data is served as visualisation and memo through Tableau and notebooks to business users
- · Presenting to the Firmwide investor protection committee on our business performance and global trends. Helping the committee with data aided decision making
- · Designed the cost model that is live now in Marquee (GS Digital Store) for internal profit assessment at the time of trade execution by Traders

2016-12 2012-06

Associate

Goldman Sachs

PBengaluru, India

- · Designing and Reporting KPIs on Business Performance and Team
- · Supported with Payoff and Terms designs for our business division to successfully launch new products and markets
- · Established control function team and process for our business unit in Bengaluru
- · Insourced legal trade documents from external legal resulting in a cost saving of around \$150,000 to the firm through automation of business

2012-06 2010-06

Research Analyst

Crisil, a S&P Company

Chennai, India

- · Founding member of Structured Trade Review team for Bank of America London Interest Rate trading desk
- · Our trade review team was awarded the "Best team of the Year" in
- · Received ACE award from S&P(parent company) for the best role model

CONTACT

J +91-9611055688

■ balamuru.peri@gmail.com

🕠 in-balamurugan

in inbalamurugan

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Scikit Learn, LGBM

2008-07 2006-06

Associate - Software developer

MindTree

Pagaluru, India

- · Enhancement and maintenance of AIG surety web site including multiple development life cycle releases; troubleshooting and fixing Adhoc bugs
- · Our team was one among five finalists for half-yearly awards in MindTree for bringing stability to the application



EDUCATION

2010 2008

MBA(Major: Finance, Minor: IT)

IIT Delhi

NewDelhi, India

- · GPA 8.25/10
- · Internship Project on Customer Feedback Analysis for Aditya Birla People Fashion Stores

2006 2002

B.E, Computer Science

Amrita School of Engineering

Ocimbatore, India

- · Percentage 76%
- · Final year project on Stochastic analysis of stock prices



DATA SCIENCE ACTIVITIES

2021

Kaggle WiDS Competition 21

Kaggle.com

· secured 45th rank(Top 6%) in competition for building machine learning model using LGBM to determine whether a patient admitted to an ICU has been diagnosed with Diabetes.

2021

Blogging

balamurugan.netlify.app

· Blogging and newsletter on tech

2019

Object Detection Training

Voluntary work

· Built and did a live demo to around a hundred Engineering students on Object detection using Telegram/Raspberry pi/Tensorflow